Guide to the Terry Sanford Papers, 1926-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Miscellaneous, 1987-1992
  - Education seminars:
    - Federal governments role, 1991-1992 (Box 140A)
    - Florida Education Reform, 1991 (Box 140A)
    - Improving American Education, 1991 (Box 140A)
    - Kentucky Education Reform, 1991 (Box 140A)
    - Lamar Alexander for Secretary of Education, 1991 (Box 140A)
    - Memos, 1990-1992 (Box 140A)
    - Names and addresses, 1991 (Box 140A)
    - National Education Reform, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 140A)
    - Seminar agendas, 1991 (Box 140A)
    - Strengthening Education for American Families Act, 1991 (Box 140A)
    - West Virginia Education Reform, 1991 (Box 140A)
  - Higher Education Colloquium on Science Facilities:
    - 1990-1992, (3 folders) (Box 140A)
    - Letters from university presidents, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 140A)
    - Support, 1987-1990 (Box 140A)
  - Mandela dinner, 1990 (Box 140A)
  - Senatorial license plate, 1992 (Box 140A)
  - Sanford basketball tourney picks, 1992 (Box 140A)
- Awards Series, 1965-1992 and undated
  Honorary degrees, awards, and certificates given to Sanford by schools and organizations.
  Unarranged.
  - Awards (Box 140B)
- Photographs Series, 1926-1992 and undated
  Chiefly photographs of Sanford with political figures. Includes a few clippings.
  - Photographs (Box 140B)
- Oversize Materials
  - Awards Series, 1965-1992 and undated (Oversize-box 1)
    Awards given between 1968-1991 (a few undated)
  - Photographs Series, 1926-1992 and undated (Oversize-box 2)
    Chiefly photographs of Sanford with political figures between 1941and 1990(some undated).
  - Miscellaneous Series, 1987-1992 (Oversize-box 3)
    Miscellaneous clippings, cartoons, and printed material, 1980's-1991 and undated
  - Photographs Series, 1926-1992 and undated, (2 folders) (Opaperfolder Folder 3)
    - Aerial photograph of Morehead City, N.C. and Wilmington, N.C., 1990 (Opaperfolder Folder 3)
  - Awards Series, 1965-1992 and undated
    - Award from the Mayor of Caen, France (undated) (Opaperfolder Folder 3)
    - Honorary Doctorate from Belmont College, 1961 (Opaperfolder Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Series, 1987-1992
    - Printed material, 1988-1990and undated (Opaperfolder Folder 3)
- Accessions 1998-0323 and 1999-0353
  - 1998-0323 (Box 1)
    - Retirement Statement (never issued) (Box 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1)
    - 517th Parachute Infantry (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Battle of the Bulge Reunion (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Memberships (Box 1)
    - Congressional Arts Caucus (Box 1)
    - Congressional Staff Club (Box 1)
    - University Club (Box 1)
    - Watauga Club Membership File (Box 1)
    - INCAE (Box 1)
    - Central American Recov. 1989 March (Box 1)
    - Central America (Box 1)
    - Education Column (Box 1)
    - Senate Project - Terry Sanford 1991 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Senate Journals, ca. 1983-1987, (39 diskettes) (Box 1)
  - 1999-0353
    - Photographs (portraits) and negatives, 1987 (Box 1)
- Accession 2000-0408
  - 1987-1990 (Box 1)
    - Senate diary, vols. 1-37, 1987 January-1990 June (Box 1)
      Some entries are handwritten; most are typed. Some entries include Senate schedules an reports.
  - 1985-1995 (Box 2)
    - Senate diary, vols. 38-51, 1990 July-1991 August (Box 2)
    - Senate logs and itineraries (Box 2)
      Includes 17 micro-cassette audio tapes.
    - Legislative reports (Box 2)
    - Constituents' correspondence (Box 2)
    - Office memoranda (Box 2)
    - Newspaper editorials (Box 2)
    - Campaign 1986and Campaign 1992material (Box 2)
- Addition, 2004 (2007-0078), 15 Boxes, 1 oversize folder
  The 2004 Addition (2007-0078) (10 linear ft., 5650 items, dated circa 1986-1996) features material related to Sanford's 1986 senatorial campaign and to his book Outlive Your Enemies (published 1996). Senatorial campaign records include correspondence, voter surveys, campaign files, clippings, event flyers and invitations, videocassettes, audiocassettes, and other materials. The Outlive Your Enemies content consists of research files related to aging.
  Some of the materials in this accession are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection. Technical Services staff need to make use copies of audiovisual material.
  - Senatorial campaign records, circa 1986-1990
    - Voter survey reports, 1986 and undated (Box 1)
    - Voter survey reports, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Voter survey reports, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Draft campaign letters (Box 3)
    - Radio advertising (Box 3)
    - Broyhill voting record (Box 3)
    - Parachute pins (Box 3)
    - Bill Green questionnaire (Box 3)
    - Advertising scripts (Box 4)
    - Clippings (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Agendas (Box 4)
    - Campaign ideas (Box 4)
    - Videocassettes, (19 items) (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Campaign files (Box 6)
    - Central America trip1987 (Box 6)
    - Event flyers and agendas (Box 6)
    - Audiocassettes, (4 items) (Box 6)
    - Voter survey reports (Box 6)
    - NCAE (Box 6)
    - Clippings (Box 6)
    - Debate invitations (Box 7)
    - Events attended (Box 7)
    - Media (Box 7)
    - Conventions and appearances (Box 7)
    - NC County files (Box 7)
    - NC County files (Box 8)
    - Voter survey reports (Box 8)
    - Voter survey reports (Box 9)
    - Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Agenda for the Nation, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Clippings (Box 10)
    - Notes (Box 10)
    - Committees (Box 10)
    - Moscow trip (Box 10)
    - Staff (Box 10)
    - Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Work on education (Box 10)
    - Invitations (Box 11)
    - Notes (Box 11)
    - Reprints (Box 11)
    - Videotape (unlabeled) (Box 11)
    - Audiocassettes, (10 items) (Box 12)
    - Campaign poster (Opaperfolder Folder 1)
  - Outlive Your Enemies research files, circa 1996
    - Notebooks (Box 13-14)
    - Aging research files (Box 13-14)
    - Clippings (Box 13-14)
    - Aging pamphlets (Box 15)
    - Aging research files (Box 15)
- Addition, 2010 (Acc. 2010-0059), 1940s-1990s, (3 boxes)
  Acc. (2010-0059) (3.6 lin. ft.; dated 1940s-1990s) includes hundreds of photographs from the Sanford family. The majority of these date from the 1980s and 1990s, while there are some earlier black and white prints from the 1940s and 1950s. Most are not labeled. There are also 2 photograph albums of family vacations to Africa (1988) and Europe (1990s). This material requires processing before use.
  - Loose photographs, 1940s-1990s (Box 1-2)
  - Family photograph album from Africa vacation, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Family photograph album from Danube River cruise (Box 3)
  - Proclamation by City of Durham regarding Sanford's Duke presidency (Box 3)
- Addition, 2012 (Acc. 2012-0001), 1960s-2000s, (1 box)
  Acc. (2012-0001) (0.2 lin. ft.; 150 items; dated 19602-2000s and undated) includes loose photographs and personal correspondence dating 1960s-2000s. The majority of these date from the 1970s. There are also miscellanous items including a 1987 Congressional Pictorial Directory. This material requires processing before use.
  This accession is closed to research pending further processing.
  - Loose photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Personal correspondence, 1960s-2000s and undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 1)
- Accession, date unknown (Acc. 2012-0056), 1991-1992, (20 boxes)
  Unprocessed addition acquired in the 1990s containing military and civilian case files from 1992.
  This accession is closed to research until processing.
  - Military veterans casework A-C (Box 1)
  - Military veterans casework C-F (Box 2)
  - Military veterans casework F-J (Box 3)
  - Military veterans casework J-M (Box 4)
  - Military veterans casework M-R (Box 5)
  - Military veterans casework R-T (Box 6)
  - Military veterans casework T-Z (Box 7)
  - Casework, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Casework, 1992 (Box 9-20)